<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[SBEPIS Documentation]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/</link><image><url>https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/lib/media/favicon.png</url><title>SBEPIS Documentation</title><link>https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/</link></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 04:42:02 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/lib/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 04:41:58 GMT</pubDate><copyright><![CDATA[Dragon & Fox Collective]]></copyright><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator>Dragon &amp; Fox Collective</dc:creator><item><title><![CDATA[Events]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Agents are aware of events, and they can reflect on those events and consider them in different contexts. For example, if information is revealed, then realizing other information about the events can affect Values through reframing.<br>
Stored as an ordered graph????<br>
Honestly the whole time system is just Skaia's AI brain.]]></description><link>https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/ai/events.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">AI/Events.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Dragon & Fox Collective]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 22:15:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Personal Values]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>TLDR a hand-made neural network.<br><br>Various traits that an agent possesses, like how Jack likes stabbing people, Leave No Witnesses, freedom, finding a hot dame.<br><br>This includes using devices that have information about other things, like fenestrated planes (which are just more agents?).<br><br>Agents love and hate different tags.<br><br>Jack must follow the Queen.<br><br>How willing an agent is to follow another agent. Jack betrays the Queen.<br><br>Jack and the Queen hate each other (/sex). See how she forces him to wear the dumb hat.<br><br>Carapacian culture is dictated by prototypings. Relies on the masses. But also it includes things like how Dersites hate the frog and Prospitians worship it.<br><br>Values set by a faction's leaders.<br><br>Internal personal political system values. Jack's hit-list, for instance, as well as wanting the Midnight Crew to operate and be big and successful, as in Spades Slick.<br><br>Receiving information is influenced by other Values, which may then change other Values (such as Emotion).<br><br>The main Value that causes agents to not work totally logically. Easily swayed.<br><br>An agent's tendency to perform large-scale actions.<br><br>Things an agent needs to survive.<br><br>Knowledge about things like artifacts. May invoke emotions and enable following through on plans. Artifacts may also have to be tested if they seem powerful.<br><br>Jobs to do within the political system. Jack has to do paperwork, but also one of his personal values is that he hates paperwork (a peon's job), decreasing his loyalty further.<br><br>Willingness to remain in the current situation.<br><br>An inverse factor of Contentedness.<br><br>Karkat gave the universe cancer, which is likely what caused Jack to become the Sovereign Slayer and blow up Skaia and stuff. Destructive impulses and murderous tendencies.]]></description><link>https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/ai/values.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">AI/Values.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Dragon & Fox Collective]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 22:53:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Bit" data-href="Bit" href="alchemy/bit.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Bits</a>]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Alchemy is a core mechanic.<br>In SBEPIS, items are stored within item cards. Items have identifiers correlating to when a player “discovered” the recipe.<br><br>An item card contains bits, defined by any of 48 holes punched in the card, and tags, defined by the qualities of the item stored inside the card. A card with no holes always contains a Perfectly Generic Object, or PGO. Bits contain information about an item’s basic function or type, such as the Handled(H) bit, which denotes an item with a component able to be wielded by players.<br><br>Some bit combinations add emergent tags.<br><br>Tags, contained within item cards, correspond to qualities about an item. These can be defined through bits (called bit tags), but also through item card data. For instance, a PGO has no bits, and thus no bit tags, but does have the Green tag, which can be inherited. Tags may also contain information relating to the original item base. Tags can be oppositional or synergistic. There may only be a certain number of tags on an item at once. Tags retain memories of what created that item, discouraging alchemical loops.<br><br>Other than bit tags are aesthetic tags, which, unlike bit tags, have a scale from 0 - 100 that determines how strongly an item inherits the traits associated with the tag. When two items are combined, the averages of tags is calculated, rounding down into whole numbers. Alchemizing an item with an item in its hereditary tree returns the same tag value. The more prominent a tag is, the more parts might be exchanged. Tags have aesthetic and form components, and perhaps materials affect things like weight and buoyancy, although minorly. As a tag gets higher or stronger, it gains secondary abilities, such as damage increases. Aspect tags are the important parts of this. Aspect tags will give an item an aspect power when strong enough.]]></description><link>https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/alchemy/alchemy.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Alchemy/Alchemy.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Dragon & Fox Collective]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 02:15:28 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Bit]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>A bit is one of 48 pieces of data represented by holes punched in an item card. These bits correspond to attributes that, together, define the base functions of an item. An item with no bits is a Perfectly Generic Object, although an object with no bits may still have <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Tag" data-href="Tag" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/alchemy/tag.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">tags</a>. Bits are listed in no particular order.<br><br>Bits are still subject to change.<br><br>A bit set is able to define emergent properties of objects with certain combinations of bits. Below are some of the bit sets so far.<br><br>Bit sets are also, naturally, subject to change.]]></description><link>https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/alchemy/bit.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Alchemy/Bit.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Dragon & Fox Collective]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 02:15:28 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Art Style Overall]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br><br><br>The character sprites, somewhere between anime and homestuck's art<br><br>Backgrounds in ACT 1 and the concept art for ACT 2, Specific assets<br><br>But softer<br><br><br><a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://babanillustration.tumblr.com/post/624998710546497536/been-working-on-these-slowly-for-the-past-2-months" target="_blank">https://babanillustration.tumblr.com/post/624998710546497536/been-working-on-these-slowly-for-the-past-2-months</a><br>
<a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.artstation.com/artwork/xJaL5m?album_id=6867835" target="_blank">https://www.artstation.com/artwork/xJaL5m?album_id=6867835</a><br>
Carapacians specifically<br>]]></description><link>https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/art-shenanigans/art-style-overall.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Art Shenanigans/Art Style Overall.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Dragon & Fox Collective]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 02:15:28 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dreamer Outfits]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br>]]></description><link>https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/art-shenanigans/dreamer-outfits.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Art Shenanigans/Dreamer Outfits.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Dragon & Fox Collective]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 07:37:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Fray]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>The Fray is a reactive timing system throughout the game, influencing other core mechanics, such as <a data-href="Combat" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/combat.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Combat</a> and <a data-href="Dialogue" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/dialogue.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Dialogue</a>. It can be affected in or out of Combat, and is the main system that the time aspect will interact with.<br>The Fray is client-side, meaning that unless players are in the same battle, they will rarely interact with the same Fray.<br>The Fray's mechanics are divided into two categories, <a data-href="#Rhythm" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/about:blank#Rhythm" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Rhythm</a> and <a data-href="#Genre" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/about:blank#Genre" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Genre</a>.<br><br>Rhythm is the means of tracking how closely the player’s <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Note" data-href="Note" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/the-fray/note.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Notes</a> match the <a data-href="Tempo" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/the-fray/tempo.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Tempo</a> and <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Time Signature" data-href="Time Signature" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/the-fray/time-signature.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Time Signatures</a> of a <a data-href="Bar" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/the-fray/bar.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Bar</a>. Keeping Rhythm does not require attacking exactly on the <a data-href="Beat" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/the-fray/beat.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Beat</a> of the Fray, but following the Rhythm rewards a bonus to <a data-href="Mana Regeneration" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/Mana Regeneration" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Mana Regeneration</a> and <a data-href="Gel Viscosity" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/Gel Viscosity" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Gel Viscosity</a> Damage.<br>Rhythm's mechanics include:<br>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Beat" data-href="Beat" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/the-fray/beat.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Beats</a>: One turn of Combat
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Bar" data-href="Bar" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/the-fray/bar.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Bars</a>: One round of Combat
<br><a data-href="Tempo" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/the-fray/tempo.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Tempo</a>: Speed of Beats
<br><br>Genre is the style of combat taking place, affecting both the note patterns of combatants and the applicable actions they can take.<br>Genre's mechanics include:<br>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Note" data-href="Note" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/the-fray/note.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Notes</a>: Individual actions combatants may take
<br><a data-href="Time Signature" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/the-fray/time-signature.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Time Signature</a>: Patterns that Beats may follow
<br><br>Having different <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Time Signature" data-href="Time Signature" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/the-fray/time-signature.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Time Signatures</a> synchronized according to single Bar is considered a Polyrhythm. A Polyrhythm audible in the Fray denotes a battle for ownership over the Fray.<br>An example of a polyrhythm would be when one player has a Time Signature of 4/4 and a Tempo of 30 BPM, and another player is in 6/4 at 45 BPM, such that the length of their Bars is the same (8 seconds).<br><br>Fighting Off-Rhythm serves the purpose of shifting control of the Fray. If you attack an opponent Off-Rhythm, it can force them to respond in ways that shake them into fighting in a different <a data-href="Time Signature" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/the-fray/time-signature.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Time Signature</a> or <a data-href="Tempo" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/the-fray/tempo.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Tempo</a> than they would be when fighting in or controlling the Fray. The more an opponent fights Off-Rhythm, the more they lose control of the Fray. After reaching a certain threshold, this will transfer control to the next most Rhythmic combatant. This makes those who do not have a good sense of Rhythm out of play still serve an important role in shaking up the battlefield.<br><br>Motifs are sequences of notes unique to particular characters or narrative themes. They can be composed together to make unique tracks focusing on a particular event or battle.<br><br>The audio engine features a live synthesizer with soundfonts and MIDI-like note sequences. Sound effects caused by actions are injected directly into the audio engine, on-beat if close enough.<br>There does need to be a visual indicator for the beat, somehow.<br>Accessibility options will include a metronome.]]></description><link>https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/the-fray/the-fray.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">The Fray/The Fray.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Dragon & Fox Collective]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 04:16:57 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Body System]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>The Body System describes several features surrounding entity models. The core idea of the system is to have an assembly of parts and joints form a character model that can be added upon, changed, or torn apart in an elegant and flexible way. A body is made up of different types of parts, Boney Landmarks and Connector Joints. <br>Gel Viscosity<br>Connectors are "joint" pieces. These pieces can be cut through with different amounts of ease. Boney Landmarks are rigid parts.<br>4 heads<br>
2 Necks (Long/Short)<br>
3 Torsos (Upper, Middle, Lower)<br>
9 Torso Connectors<br>
3 Shoulders<br>
3 Hips<br>
3 knees<br>
3 ankles<br>
Upper Arm<br>
Lower Arm<br>
5 Upper extremities (hands)<br>
Wrist<br>
Elbow<br>
Rubber-hose arms (tentacles etc)<br>
Rubber-hose legs<br>
5 lower extremities (feet)<br>
Wings (4 parts)<br>
Tail<br>
General all purpose deco (functional bit set (eyes)) ]]></description><link>https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/body-system.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Body System.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Dragon & Fox Collective]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 02:15:28 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Combat]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>A generated event involving at least one aggressor, one target, and a combat goal. Combat participation is optional. Combat will begin when initiated by a single party, and <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Teams and Combatants" data-href="#Teams and Combatants" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/about:blank#Teams_and_Combatants" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">combatants</a> involved will be assigned depending on various traits. Combat will not be restricted to <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Event Chunk" data-href="Event Chunk" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/Event Chunk" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Event Chunks</a>, but will aim to fit within them. When an entity becomes aware of an aggressor, they will be prompted to <a data-href="#Strife" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/about:blank#Strife" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Strife</a> or <a data-href="#Abscond" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/about:blank#Abscond" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Abscond</a>.<br><a data-href="The Fray" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/the-fray/the-fray.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Fray</a> will inform how combat is approached by setting the pace and difficulty of a battle. Enemies will tend to attack on <a data-href="Beat" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/the-fray/beat.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Beat</a>, although they may have different <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Tempo" data-href="Tempo" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/the-fray/tempo.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Tempos</a>. <a data-href="#Swarmers" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/about:blank#Swarmers" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Swarmers</a> will adjust the Tempo according to factional relationships. <a data-href="#Commanders" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/about:blank#Commanders" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Commanders</a> can set the Tempo for the Swarmers they lead, such as Waltz Time or Common Time.<br>Projectile weapons will use Ammo if available, but you can also get an upgrade to create Ammunition from your <a data-href="Grist" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/grist.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Grist</a> stores. Projectile weapons only shoot when using piercing attacks. Directional attacks would be swinging the gun. (Edge case I got caught up on: A rocket launcher will shoot when using a non-directional attack. Projectiles can change course-- But this would be described elsewhere, not determined actively by the player.) Imagine directly hitting someone vs happening to hit someone indirectly.<br><br>Recoil, knockback, slides, and more. Innate movement encompasses running, sprinting, jumping, crouching, and sliding… Satisfactory-style crouch bhopping is also innate. Niche movement abilities will be supported, but optional in the form of alchemized gear, including dashing. Special body parts such as wings would be considered gear for this purpose.<br><br>Every weapon has light, heavy, and special attacks.<br>
<br>Special attacks are used when weapons are not locked on to a target (reloads, special attacks, other misc actions) Uses your current movement to do a certain attack.
<br>Piercing attacks are from the camera forwards– IE, non directional movement. Imagine a sword jab vs an arced attack. Instead of calculating armor, you’re looking for weak points/unarmored points. 
<br>Light attacks (for projectiles, this is shooting), they’re always forward facing/ cannot be directional
<br>Heavy attacks will be directional. They can influence direction while attacking, unlike special attacks, which only account for direction, not change it.
<br>Combinations of bits will assign a weapon a strife specibus type, which thus determines the function of light/heavy/special attacks
<br><br>The player has a radial picker based on Horizons that allows them to switch between contexts for weapons, weapon firing modes, and <a data-href="Dialogue" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/dialogue.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Dialogue</a>.<br><br>
<br>Directional Attacks have 27 variations (Forward, Backward, Left, Right, Up, Down, All Diagonals and Not Moving)
<br>Parts have Gel Viscosity that can be depleted to deal a crit. If a crit on a 0 GV part destroys the limb/joint, potentially killing the target, a gib system will be activated.
<br>“Lock on” function will lock on to target closest to center of screen, prioritizing Boss &gt; Commander &gt; Swarmer
<br>Which hit box do you hit, and how close to the center of the hit box are you? 
<br>A directional attack is more likely to chop off vs a non directional attack, which is more likely to pierce through
<br>Armour and parts will have directional weak points, IE, a carapacian with an armored head would be more resistant to downward directional attacks.
<br><br><br>The Commander is, for all intents and purposes, a boss within a combat scenario. Because bosses will be diverse, the play style efficiency will depend on the boss. Commanders within an event chunk will have levels of importance. Lower importance means lower chances of successfully commanding a swarm. High importance increases likelihood of command success, but also… Commander tactics in battle will be determined by:<br>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="The Fray > Genre" data-href="The Fray#Genre" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/the-fray/the-fray.html#Genre" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Genre</a>
<br>Personal Goals
<br>Politics
<br>Team Numbers or Ratios
<br><br>Swarmers will be the bulk of enemy teams. The <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="The Fray > Rhythm" data-href="The Fray#Rhythm" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/the-fray/the-fray.html#Rhythm" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Rhythm</a> of Swarmers is controlled by the Commanders controlling them, although the <a data-href="Tempo" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/the-fray/tempo.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Tempo</a> is usually dictated by Factional Relationship to PC. Swarmers will form clouds of AI groups. When in Combat, Swarmers will tend to group together. If a Commander is present, Swarmer AI will be dependent on Commander Tactics. Limited AI with seeded randomness.<br>Examples of Swarmers include:<br>
<br>Imps: Do not carry items but will have mutations. Faction leader is the Denizen.
<br>Basilisks, Liches, Giclopses, Ogres
<br>Carapacians: Equipment loadouts AND mutations
<br>Consorts: Do not mutate without Commander Intervention. Carry items and equipment loadouts.
<br><br>Combat begins when both parties are aware of an encounter. Teams are generated depending on the initiate parties.<br><br>Key choice made by evaluation of enemies, factions, power, tempo, etc.<br>A combat event will conclude with an end condition, either the death of the aggressor party or target party, the satiation of the aggressor party (calmed) or the target party (spared), fleeing, knock-out.<br>
<br>Fleeing - Extra damage against fleeing targets
<br>Knocked Out - Attacks kill knocked out targets
<br><br>What’s the goal of abjuration?<br>
<br>Dialogue - Dialogue abjuration will involve a defensive playstyle and quick dialogue choices. The goal of this must also be determined, but it can usually be assumed the goal is non-violent resolution and higher relationship and factional relationship.
<br>Knockout - Goal of this is non-lethal defeat of enemies. Enemies will not be killed when defeated. This can be for a variety of tactical reasons.
<br><br>Tactical escapes, enemies will give chase! What’s the best way to leave?<br>
<br>Will the enemy type give chase? Are you a target?
<br>What abilities do enemies have compared to players? Teleports?
<br>Is there a team looking for you now? Will this affect factional relationships? Regular relationships? Increase importance?
<br><br>The goal is to kill, the question is how?<br>
<br>Team Numbers - Are we outnumbered? By how much?
<br>Presence of Commanders - Will the commanders also be killed? (combat stance related,) Are the enemies organized or disorganized?
<br>Enemy types - What types of damage will be most effective?
<br><br>Teams are created on battle start, but are also dynamic within an event chunk. Team placement will depend on various factors, such as faction relationships, player relationships, strife choice, and targets of attack. <br>Combatants involved in a combat event will be determined by how many combatants are within the event chunk. The event chunk will read the Time value depending on the combatants within the chunk and their time-related abilities. When an event chunk contains no combatants that have time-related abilities, only the SCT time will be read.<br>
Teams will include aggressor parties and target parties initially, and each of these teams will have defined intents to kill.]]></description><link>https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/combat.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Combat.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Dragon & Fox Collective]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 04:14:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dialogue]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>The dialogue system uses the <a data-href="Roleplay" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/roleplay.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Roleplay</a> system to generate text based on NPCs' personalities and potential responses based on the players' personalities.<br>Emotional or objective context may be changed by using the <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Combat > Stances" data-href="Combat#Stances" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/combat.html#Stances" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Stance Wheel</a> prior to engaging in dialogue.<br>Dialogue is also a critical part of <a data-href="Combat" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/combat.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Combat</a>, as sometimes it is better to peacefully resolve a dispute, but also you can use it to shout commands to your teammates or NPC cohorts.]]></description><link>https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/dialogue.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Dialogue.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Dragon & Fox Collective]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 04:15:59 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Exile Terminals]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Diagetically, the players control their characters by taking the place of carapacian exiles, feeding prompts through a terminal, although as direct movement inputs. Also as diagetically, the players may control these exiles a layer of terminal removed. This is where most pause menu functionality goes. Additionally, when the player is controlling their exile, their character becomes controlled by <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Values" data-href="Values" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/ai/values.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">AI</a> as to not interrupt gameplay for everyone else involved.]]></description><link>https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/exile-terminals.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Exile Terminals.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Dragon & Fox Collective]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 04:21:47 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Grist]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 ]]></description><link>https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/grist.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Grist.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Dragon & Fox Collective]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 02:15:28 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Index]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Welcome to the SBEPIS documentation!<br>SBEPIS is a fan-made, first-person implementation of "SBURB," the game from Andrew Hussie's web comic Homestuck. The goal of SBEPIS's development is to complete several hard tasks that other SBURB sims haven't done, such as comprehensive AI and procedural alchemy.<br>SBEPIS is a traditional roguelike, adventure, immersive simulation game. "Traditional roguelike" in this case means having 20 hour runs that might end due to any mistake and having to learn over many many instances.<br>SBEPIS is in Pre-Alpha and does not have a timeline for full release. Information within the documentation is not exhaustive and is subject to change at any point. <br>Join the SBEPIS <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://discord.gg/qHREQu7Zxm" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://discord.gg/qHREQu7Zxm" target="_blank">Discord</a>! Developer streams, news, and discussions can be found there, as well as an active community of Homestuck fans, furries, and gamers! It's also the best place to give feedback, support, ideas, or ask questions!<br>The full source code of SBEPIS is available on <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://github.com/Dragon-Fox-Collective/SBEPIS" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://github.com/Dragon-Fox-Collective/SBEPIS" target="_blank">GitHub</a>.]]></description><link>https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Index.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Dragon & Fox Collective]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 02:50:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Kiddie Camper Handysash]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>This is essentially the achievement repository. Some achievements grant boons, similar to Gift of Gab.]]></description><link>https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/kiddie-camper-handysash.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Kiddie Camper Handysash.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Dragon & Fox Collective]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 01:35:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Roleplay]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Named after the <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://archiveofourown.org/works/340777/chapters/685537" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://archiveofourown.org/works/340777/chapters/685537" target="_blank">Roleplay System</a> from <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://archiveofourown.org/works/340777/chapters/551606" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://archiveofourown.org/works/340777/chapters/551606" target="_blank">SBURB Glitch FAQ</a>, the roleplay system both grasps each player character's identity and ensures that the players play according to the characters they've created.<br>For example, the system determines that a character should be a knight of life based on NPC interactions and playstyle. From this, their life-based spells such as healing or sapping are more effective in combat and less effective elsewhere.<br>For another example, a player harmfully exploits consorts (either in or out of character). Because of this, the consorts will start to distrust the player and will be more hostile, requiring the player to earn back favor.<br>The roleplay system ties in nicely with the <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Values" data-href="Values" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/ai/values.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">AI</a> system.<br><br><a data-href="Dialogue" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/dialogue.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Dialogue</a> is one way to understand what the player's character is like.<br><br><br>Another way to glean information about a player's character is directly receiving their inner monologue. We are doing this by providing a diary, or "dream journal", to players in their dream towers, which they must complete in order to wake up. The dream journal uses the <a data-href="Dialogue" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/dialogue.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Dialogue</a> system to have the player recap events that have transpired and provide their feelings on them.]]></description><link>https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/roleplay.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Roleplay.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Dragon & Fox Collective]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 04:19:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Installation]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>During the installation process, the player must answer a series of questions that determines dream moon, land challenge, and core character traits. This was originally planned to be the tutorial for the dream journal, but you can't exactly determine the moon when you're on the moon...]]></description><link>https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/sburb.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">SBURB.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Dragon & Fox Collective]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 04:05:39 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sylladex]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>The old sylladex used a literal deck of cards with a holographic table. While very cool, this has usability issues, since you need space to lay everything out and to throw the deck.<br>The new sylladex is a digital interface on an arm-mounted holographic device. This allows us to use literal cartridges again, while having a compact and still-vaguely-diagetic inventory.<br>Cards may be interacted with as if they were physical objects, and may actually be pulled out and enlarged into physical cards. The same applies for putting cards in.<br>Captchaloguing an item involves either aiming at or holding an item and pressing the captchalouge button. This marks it with an outline until fetch modus requirements are completed. Once the fetch modi are satisfied, the captcha'd object is shrunk down and placed inside a card, which then moves to its appropriate position in the deck.]]></description><link>https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/sylladex.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Sylladex.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Dragon & Fox Collective]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 04:36:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Marching Cubes]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>We have two main options on how terrain may be generated.<br><br>One option is to use a cube grid around the entire universe (or perhaps many small local grids) and the marching cubes algorithm to smooth out hard corners. I think this is what they do in No Man's Sky.<br>However, this might not be very usable for things that fall off-grid or are too small to fit on the grid, and having too big of a grid might consume too much RAM.<br><br>The other option is to forego a grid entirely and operate directly on mesh data. This might be more usable for SBURB since you can alter orientation and length however you might need to. This also has the benefit of allowing objects to be physics-compatible, since they don't need to adhere to a grid.<br>However, this is known for being very slow... unless we can find a way around that.]]></description><link>https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/terrain.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Terrain.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Dragon & Fox Collective]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 04:27:14 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Aesthetic Tag]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>A tag holds arbitrary data about an object. These can be created through <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Bit" data-href="Bit" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/alchemy/bit.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">bits</a> (called bit tags), but also through item card data. For instance, a PGO has no bits, but does have the Green tag, which can be inherited. Tags may also contain information relating to the original item base. Tags can be oppositional or synergistic. Tags retain memories of what created that item, discouraging alchemical loops.<br><br>Aesthetic tags are a type of tag that can describe the appearance, bonuses, and non-aspect related powers of an object within an item card. The number of these tags is limited, although by what measure is undecided. Importantly, aesthetic tags can have a magnitude of 0 - 100. Aesthetic tags also define physical properties, such as weight or density, and combined with the tag magnitude, will also comprise a key function within the physics system. Each tag has its own grist cost, with the upper limit cost corresponding with a magnitude of 100.<br>This list is an in-progress list of aesthetic tags that have been planned for SBEPIS.<br>]]></description><link>https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/alchemy/tag.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Alchemy/Tag.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Dragon & Fox Collective]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 19:20:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Training Imp]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>One <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Dialogue" data-href="Dialogue" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/Dialogue" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">dialogue tree</a> that causes combat to start and stop
<br>Can <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Combat" data-href="Combat" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/combat.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">kill</a> and drop grist and weapon
<br>Can react to player using a weapon, ultimately also using that same weapon
<br>The player can pick the imp's <a data-href="Time Signature" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/the-fray/time-signature.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Time Signature</a>
]]></description><link>https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/entities/training-imp.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Entities/Training Imp.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Dragon & Fox Collective]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 19:20:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Bar]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>A Bar is a unit of time representing one round of <a data-href="Combat" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/combat.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Combat</a>, comprised of a number of <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Beat" data-href="Beat" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/the-fray/beat.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Beats</a> based on a <a data-href="Time Signature" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/the-fray/time-signature.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Time Signature</a>. <a data-href="Ability" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/Ability" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Ability</a> cooldowns finish as Bars end. <a data-href="The Fray" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/the-fray/the-fray.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">The Fray</a> can be exchanged between actors at the end of a Bar. This is also when AIs may change behaviors.<br><a data-href="Dialogue" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/Dialogue" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Dialogue</a> as a whole follows a pattern over Bars, even if saying lines are appropriate as Beats.]]></description><link>https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/the-fray/bar.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">The Fray/Bar.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Dragon & Fox Collective]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 19:20:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Beat]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>A Beat is a unit of time representing one turn of <a data-href="Combat" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/combat.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Combat</a>. Actions and dialogue (called "<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Note" data-href="Note" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/the-fray/note.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Notes</a>") have a length of time in <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Beat" data-href="Beat" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/the-fray/beat.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Beats</a>. Lengths of Beats themselves are dependent on the <a data-href="Tempo" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/the-fray/tempo.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Tempo</a> and <a data-href="Time Signature" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/the-fray/time-signature.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Time Signature</a> of a particular combatant. Combatants will TEND to fight On-Rhythm unless fighting reactively or attempting to throw an opponent <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="The Fray > Fighting Off-Rhythm" data-href="The Fray#Fighting Off-Rhythm" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/the-fray/the-fray.html#Fighting_Off-Rhythm" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Off-Rhythm</a>.]]></description><link>https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/the-fray/beat.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">The Fray/Beat.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Dragon & Fox Collective]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 19:20:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Example Tempos]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>The Tempo is the speed of a combatant's <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Beat" data-href="Beat" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/the-fray/beat.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Beats</a> and <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Bar" data-href="Bar" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/the-fray/bar.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Bars</a>. It is paced by the strongest fighter(s) as they own the <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="The Fray" data-href="The Fray" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/the-fray/the-fray.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Fray</a>. Desperation, intensity, difficulty, and proximity to an <a data-href="Event Chunk" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/Event Chunk" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Event Chunk</a> all correlate positively with Tempo. Tempo can also be increased during arguments, chases, or escapes.<br><br><br>Common time is the most familiar Tempo to most people. It uses a straightforward 4/4 <a data-href="Time Signature" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/the-fray/time-signature.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Time Signature</a>.<br><br>This is a stub.]]></description><link>https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/the-fray/tempo.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">The Fray/Tempo.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Dragon & Fox Collective]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 19:20:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Time Signature]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>The Time Signature is the number of <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Beat" data-href="Beat" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/the-fray/beat.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Beats</a> in a combatant's <a data-href="Bar" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/the-fray/bar.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Bar</a>. Having a larger Time Signature generally implies a faster <a data-href="Tempo" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/the-fray/tempo.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Tempo</a>.<br>Multiple Time Signatures may exist in the Fray simultaneously, resulting in <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="The Fray > Polyrhythms" data-href="The Fray#Polyrhythms" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/the-fray/the-fray.html#Polyrhythms" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Polyrhythms</a>.<br>The denominator of the Time Signature is always 4, meaning Beats are always counted as quarter notes.]]></description><link>https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/the-fray/time-signature.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">The Fray/Time Signature.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Dragon & Fox Collective]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 19:20:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Training Dummy]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Has a shield that can block <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Combat > Accuracy" data-href="Combat#Accuracy" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/combat.html#Accuracy" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Directional Attacks</a>
]]></description><link>https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/entities/training-dummy.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Entities/Training Dummy.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Dragon & Fox Collective]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 18:54:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Note]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Any action a <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Combat" data-href="Combat" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/combat.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">combatant</a> takes is considered a Note. Light Attacks are represented by quarter notes (one <a data-href="Beat" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/the-fray/beat.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Beat</a>), Heavy Attacks are half notes (two <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Beat" data-href="Beat" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/the-fray/beat.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Beats</a>), and Special Attacks are full notes (one <a data-href="Bar" href="https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/the-fray/bar.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Bar</a>).]]></description><link>https://dragon-fox-collective.github.io/SBEPIS-docs/the-fray/note.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">The Fray/Note.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Dragon & Fox Collective]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 18:54:02 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>